the-mommyhood-chronicles.com 2019-05-13

# Disclosure/Privacy Policy - The Mommyhood Chronicles

**Privacy Policy**

The Mommyhood Chronicles  is committed to protecting your privacy and ensuring the security of information you submit to us. Our Privacy Policy informs you about how and why we collect any personal information about you, and how we use that information. Your accessing and continued use of our site signifies your explicit consent to these terms and conditions and data practices of our Privacy Policy. This privacy policy applies to the website  The Mommyhood Chronicles.

**Registration:  **

We do not require registration in order to browse on our site.

**Information Collected and How it is Used**

  * _Information You Voluntarily Submit on the Website:_ We may collect personal information when you register with us, and when you use our services, such as you name and email address. This may occur when you submit a contact us form, submit a comment on a blog post, or subscribing to our newsletter. Additionally, we may use your personal information as set forth in the registration section above.

  * _Information We Collect from Others/Third Party Partners or Vendors:_ We may receive information about you from other sources. For example, if you use a third-party software through the site, such as an online store or a scheduling application, they may transfer information to us for fulfillment, etc.

  * _Automatically-Collected and Stored Information_ **:** We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. When you use the Website, the information we collect may include your IP address, operating system type, browser type, domain names, referring website, pages you viewed, access time, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.

  * _Cookies:_ We may process information using cookies. A cookie is a small data file that we download to your computer, containing information about you to facilitate interaction with our site and services. Cookies make it possible for us to store contents of your shopping cart until you are ready to check out, and to recognize your browser when you visit. By doing this, we can personalize your visits and save you time during checkout. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted. If you reject the cookie, you may still use our site. However, in order to enjoy the benefits of being a registered user, your browser must be set to accept cookies.

**Use of Your Information**

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

  * To operate and maintain the Website;
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters, surveys, and marketing material. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries;
  * To provide you with user support;
  * To track and measure advertising on the Website
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

**Sensitive Personal Information**

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

**Your Rights Related to Your Personal Information**

  * _Opt-out_ : You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at mchronicles1@gmail.com to be removed from our mailing list.
  * _Access:_ You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to  mchronicles1@gmail.com
  * _Amend/Change:_ You may contact us at mchronicles1@gmail.com to amend or update your personal information. You may also re-subscribe and update your subscription profile to update your personal information.
  * _Forget_ : In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to mchronicles1@gmail.com
  * Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

The Mommyhood Chronicles will not rent, sell, or share your personal information with other people or nonaffiliated companies except to provide products or services that you have requested, or unless we have your explicit permission as agreed to in this Privacy Policy or otherwise. If you submit a different address for shipping than for billing, the shipping information is only used to ship the package. The Mommyhood Chronicles may share personal information with contractors or trusted service providers who work with us under confidentiality agreements to fulfill your order. The Mommyhood Chronicles may also contract with vendors to help us analyze traffic and usage of our site, communicate with you about offers and services from The Mommyhood Chronicles, and to help us provide better services. These companies will not be provided any independent right to use or share personal information. We may share personal information without notice in order to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal service of process; or to establish or exercise our legal rights, protect the property of The Mommyhood Chronicles, and/or to defend against legal claims. The Mommyhood Chronicles also may share personal information when we believe it necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Service, or as otherwise required by law. In addition, we may transfer information about you if we are acquired by, reorganized or merged with another company. In that event, we will notify active registered users if there is a need to change this Privacy Policy.

_Specific Third Party Use_

Additionally, The Mommyhood Chronicles may use third-party service providers service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is subject to their respective privacy policies. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of those sites you choose to link to from The Mommyhood Chronicles before providing your personal information to them so that you can understand how those unaffiliated sites collect, use and share your information. The Mommyhood Chronicles currently uses the following third-party service providers:

  * Google Analytics – this service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.
  * Payment Processing/Online Store/Subscription Platform – this service is used to serve our ecommerce platform. At no time is your banking information passed to the Website. We receive only information used for order fulfillment.
  * [EMAIL SERVICE PROVIDER] – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications.

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Company’s sole discretion.

**Anonymous Info/Data**

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

**Publicly Visible Info**

If you create a user profile on the Website or leave a comment, certain information may be publicly visible.

**Advertising on The Mommyhood Chronicles: FOR ALL OF THESE THINGS, YOU NEED TO CHECK WITH YOUR THIRD PARTY PROVIDERS TO ENSURE ACCURACY IN THE STATEMENTS BELOW.**

_Display Ads:_ We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies. No personally identifiable information is shared with the Website’s ad providers.

_Retargeting Ads:_ From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

_Sponsored Content Tracking Pixels:_ This Website may engage in sponsored campaigns with various influencer networks, brands, and agencies. Company makes it a policy to disclose all sponsored content in accordance with the Federal Trade Commission’s (FTC) requirements. From time to time, these sponsored campaigns utilize tracking pixels (aka web beacons), which may contain cookies to collect data regarding usage and audience. This information is collected by the sponsoring company to track the results of the campaign with Company. No personally identifiable information collected by the Website is used in conjunction with these tracking pixels.

_Affiliate Program Participation_ : [LIST ALL AFFILIATE PROGRAMS YOU MAY USE] The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales or visits for purposes of commissions.

The Mommyhood Chronicles is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com. As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

_Newsletters_ : On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

**Children Under Sixteen**

The Mommyhood Chronicles does not intentionally target our site or our services to children, and The Mommyhood Chronicles will not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of sixteen. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at mchronicles1@gmail.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

**Use of Information**

The Mommyhood Chronicles collects and uses your personal information to operate its website(s) and to deliver the services that you have requested.The Mommyhood Chronicles uses your personal information to fulfill your requests for products and services, to improve our services, to customize the advertising and content you see, and to contact you.The Mommyhood Chronicles uses anonymous information, such as that pertaining to web pages viewed, to analyze trends, to track user’s movements, to provide a better website experience and to gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. The Mommyhood Chronicles and its affiliates do not use this data in a manner that would identify you personally. Your product reviews, comments and any other information you make available in public areas of our website likely will be seen by people and organizations not related to or controlled by The Mommyhood Chronicles.The Mommyhood Chronicles may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or new potential services or products that may be offered.

**Security**

When our registration or order forms ask you to enter sensitive information (such as credit card number), that information is encrypted for transmission. When you provide information via these forms, we use SSL encryption and this should be indicated by a ‘lock’ icon in web browsers such Microsoft Internet Explorer, Google Chrome, Safari, and Mozilla Firefox.

**Updates to this Policy**

The Mommyhood Chronicles may occasionally update this policy to reflect Company and consumer feedback. The Mommyhood Chronicles encourages you to periodically review this policy for changes and to be informed of howThe Mommyhood Chronicles is protecting your information.

**Questions and Suggestions**

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, then you can contact us at mchronicles1@gmail.com, or you can send a letter toThe Mommyhood Chronicles with your questions or concerns.

This Privacy Policy was last updated May 2018.
